varnish-software.com 2019-12-12

# Privacy policy | Varnish Software

## Varnish Software privacy policy

This privacy policy applies to both our websites (Websites), and our customer data. It governs our data collection, processing and usage practices. By using the Websites you consent to the data practices described in this privacy policy. If you do not agree with the data practices described in this privacy policy, you should not use the Websites.

We may occasionally update this privacy policy so please revisit it from time to time. If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our treatment of the information you provide us, please write to us at [info@varnish-software.com](mailto:info@varnish-software.com).

####  **1\. Information collected by Varnish Software**

####  **1.1 Personal information**

You are free to explore the Websites without providing any “personal information” about yourself. This refers to any information that you voluntarily submit to us and that identifies you personally, including contact information, such as your name, e-mail address, company name, address, phone number, and other information about yourself or your business. Personal information can also include information about you that is available on the internet, such as from Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and Google.

####  **1.2. Navigational information**

This refers to information about your computer and your visits to this website such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and pages viewed. Please see the “Navigation information” section below.

####  **1.3. Payment Information**

We collect and process payment information from you when you register to attend one of our events or e-learning courses, including credit card numbers and billing information, using third party PCI-compliant service providers. Except for this, we do not collect sensitive information from you.

####  **2\. How information is used**

We use the information we collect only in compliance with this privacy policy. We will never sell your personal information to any third party. In addition to the uses identified elsewhere in this privacy policy, we may use your personal information to: (a) improve your browsing experience by personalizing the Websites (b) send information to you which we think may be of interest to you by post, email, or other means; (c) send you marketing communications relating to our business or the businesses of carefully-selected third parties which we think may be of interest to you, and (d) provide other companies with statistical information about our users — but this information will not be used to identify any individual user.

Further, Varnish Software may share your information with its trusted [partners](http://www.varnish-software.com/partners/) under strict confidential rules to provide you with the best possible local services or support according to your needs. In no case will your information be shared with anyone outside of Varnish Software or its partners.

####  **2.1. Use of navigational information**

We use navigational information to operate and improve the Websites. We may also use navigational information alone or in combination with personal information to provide you with personalized information about Varnish Software’s offerings.

####  **2.2. Customer testimonials and comments**

We post customer testimonials and comments on our Websites, which may contain personal information. We obtain each customer’s consent prior to posting the customer’s name and testimonial.

####  **2.3. Use of credit card Information**

If you give us credit card information, we use it solely to check your financial qualifications and collect payment from you. We use a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use information you provide except for the sole purpose of credit-card processing of your specific, authorized transaction on our behalf.

####  **2.4. Security of your personal information**

We make efforts to safeguard your personal information and we use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect it from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at info@varnish-software.com.

####  **2.5. Social media features**

Our Websites include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our sites. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. These features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Websites. This privacy policy does not apply to these features.  Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy and other policies of the companies providing them.

####  **2.6. External websites**

Our Websites provide links to other websites. Our provision of such links does not constitute our endorsement of these other websites, their content, their owners, or their practices. This privacy policy does not apply to these other websites, which are subject to the privacy or other policies of those other websites.

####  **2.7. Public forums**

We offer publicly accessible blogs and community forums. Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose any information through our blogs or forums, this information may be collected and used by others.

####  **2.8. Retention of personal information**

We retain personal information that you provide us as long as we consider it potentially useful in contacting you about the product and services we provide or as needed to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. We will delete this information from the servers if you so request, as described in “Opting Out and Unsubscribing” below.

####  **2.9. International transfer of information**

To facilitate our global operations, we may transfer and access personal information from around the world, including the United States. This privacy policy shall apply even if we transfer personal information to other countries.

####  **2.10. Corporate events**

If Varnish Software is acquired by another company, whether by merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or otherwise, that company would receive all information gathered by Varnish Software on the Websites. In this event, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership.

####  **2.11. Compelled disclosure**

We reserve the right to use or disclose your personal information if required by law or if we reasonably believe that use or disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or comply with a law, court order, or legal process.

####  **3\. Navigational information**

####  **3.1. Cookies**

By use of cookies Varnish Software collects anonymous, non-confidential, and non-personal information when you use our site or send us emails. Cookies are small computer files that are transferred to your computer’s hard drive to allow us to know how often someone visits a site and the activities they conduct while on the site. Every computer is assigned a different cookie. There are two types of cookies. One which saves a file on your computer for a long time. This is used, for example, for functions that tell you what is new since the user last visited that particular website. The other type is called a session cookie. During the time you visit a site, this cookie is saved temporarily in the memory of your computer, for example to keep track of what language you have chosen. Session cookies are not stored for a long time on your computer, but disappear when you close your web browser. The information collected by cookies allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our site, or are opening our emails. We may use cookie information to target certain advertisements to your browser or to determine the popularity of certain content or advertisements. It may be possible to link non-personal cookie information to personal information collected. You can deactivate cookies in your browser, but this may hinder our ability to provide you with certain services or your ability to enjoy certain features of the websites.

The use of cookies and web beacons by any tracking utility company is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these third party tracking technologies.

####  **3.2. Log files**

We may collect demographic information, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites using log files that are not associated with your name or other personal information. Information about your computer hardware and software is also automatically collected. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, internet service provider (ISP), the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, clickstream data, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used to provide general statistics regarding use of the Varnish Software Website. For these purposes, we do link this automatically-collected data to personal information such as name, email address, address, and phone number.

####  **4\. Opting out and unsubscribing**

####  **4.1. Reviewing, correcting and removing your personal information**

Upon your request, Varnish Software will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If you provide us with your personal information, you have the following rights with respect to that information:

  * To review the user information that you have supplied to us
  * To request that we correct any errors, outdated information, or omissions in user information that you have supplied to us
  * To request that your user information is not be used to contact you
  * To request that your user information be removed from any solicitation list that we use
  * To request that your user information be deleted from our records
  * To opt out of being solicited by Varnish Software

To exercise any of these rights, please contact us at [info@varnish-software.com](mailto:info@varnish-software.com). We will respond to your request to change, correct, or delete your information within a reasonable time frame and notify you of the action we have taken.

####  **4.2. To unsubscribe from our communications**

You may unsubscribe from our marketing communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of our e-mails. Attention: Customers cannot opt out of receiving transactional emails related to their subscription contract with us.

####  **4.3 The tools used to create the Varnish Software website**

[www.varnish-software.com](http://www.varnish-software.com/) is created with[ WordPress](https://drupal.org/), running on Varnish, Apache, MySQL and PHP.

### Contact us

London +44 20 3950 6173  
New York +1 646 586 2052  
Stockholm +46 8 410 909 30  
Paris +33 1 70 75 27 81

  Contact us
